PERSONAL PROFILE

A multilingual, cross- cultural Business Development professional with a track-record of successful closed sales opportunities, exceeding targets across multiple regions. Fluent to a business level in 3 languages (incl. German) and revamping hi-tech multinationals' business portfolios. Experienced in International Business development and E-commerce Account Management. Currently open to new opportunities.

EXPERIENCE

Car Salesman

Dream Motoring World, UK

July 2023 – Present

- Maintaining reporting structures and recording sales and inventory on our CRM software.
- Maintaining a customer database to track interactions with clients.
- Building a rapport with potential customers to improve the possibility of future sales and strengthen client relationships.
- Manage multiple assignments- Monitoring and communicating work status changes to Editors/ Managers.
- Understanding the characteristics, capabilities, and features of all cars, providing the potential customer with detailed information, including comparing different competitive models.
- In depth knowledge and consistent learning of Product Portfolio.

Business Development Executive

Salesforce, UK Dec 2022 – July 2023

- Qualified leads from marketing campaigns as sales opportunities and contacting potential clients through cold calls and emails.
- Identified client needs and suggest appropriate products/services.
- Customised product solutions to increase customer satisfaction.
- Hands-on experience with multiple sales techniques (including outbound calls) and a record of achieving sales quotas.
- Excellent communication and negotiation skills and the ability to deliver engaging presentations.

Assistant Store Manager

O2, UK Sep 2021 – Dec 2022

- Maintained a daily record of all transactions and generated reports for the store manager.
- Analyzed marketing information and translated and implemented strategic plans for customer growth.
- Revamped O2's business portfolio throughout the Southern region by hitting 150%, 320% and 220% against group target and generating £120K revenue in Q4.
- Assisted with recruitment and training of new staff.
- Managed multiple deadlines in a fast-paced environment and easily adapted to changing priorities.

TBA, UK Jan 2021 – Aug 2021

- Responsible for identifying opportunities for high-tech companies through targeted cold calls, email, and LinkedIn.
- Utilised CRM in depth to create opportunities, leads and follow up (Salesforce, SalesLoft, ZoomInfo, LinkedIn, SalesNav, DemandBase).
- Worked with our regional AE's and account managers to generate new business for EMEA.
- Supported international business growth by establishing new & creative solutions in an everchanging e-commerce customer climate.
- Generated £260K worth of opportunities in the pipeline for Q1 & Q2 (hit 100% quota MoM).
- Followed up on Marketing qualified leads to set up product demos for our Account Executives.

Security Guard

TSS Security, UK May 2019 – Dec 2020

- Worked within a wider team of 15 to maintain building security via the provision of onsite presence, execution of routine patrols and security checks.

- Allowing entry only of authorised vendors, contractors and visitors through proper security checks and the close monitoring of CCTV cameras and access systems.
- Assessing the security needs of emergency situations and acting accordingly whilst maintaining confidentiality.
- Managed multiple assignments- Monitor and communicate work status changes to supervisors and managers.
- Prepared status reports by gathering, analysing, and summarising relevant information.
- Managed deadlines in a fast-paced environment and easily adapted to changing priorities.

EDUCATION

University of Portsmouth Sept 2020 – July 2023

BA (Hons) Business Management & Entrepreneurship.

Saint Francis Xavier College Sept 2018 – June 2020

BTEC Business Diploma (Distinction).

Blenheim High School, Epsom, UK Sept 2013 – July 2018

GCSE– Math, English, German, Philosophy & Ethics, Sociology and Business Studies.

INTERESTS & LANGUAGES

- Multilingual- German (Native), Urdu (Native), Punjabi (Native), English (Fluent).
- **Volunteering** Social Media Management- Humanity First. Revamping the organisation's communication strategy on Social Media Outlets, including managing Global campaigns.
- **Sport** Boxing, Football.
- Writing- Short narrative English Essays.
- Radio/ Web- Voice of Islam.